...]
NARRATOR:
Two decades had passed
since the creation of both species.
The war had begun.
Viktor increased his army,
creating a legion of vampires
to protect them
from the very first clan
of werewolves:
A vicious and
infectious breed unable
to take human form ever again.
Until he was born.
[GROWLING]
Lucian.
And although every fiber of Viktor's
soul warned him to slay this child,
he did not.
Over the years, this child grew.
He possessed a strength and focus
that the ones before him did not.
[GRUNTING]
What do you think, Sonja?
Shall we make more?
Of him?
Like him.
Lucian will always be
the first of the breed,
the first of the Lycans.
Viktor would use Lucian's
infectious blood to his benefit,
taking advantage
of the child's thirst,
pitting it against him as he
was forced to feed on humans,
Viktor's slaves.
MAN 1: Get in there.
MAN 2: In there.
[GROWLING]
Instead, he created a new race
of immortals:
Lycans.
Werewolf, but also human.
Unlike the others,
this new breed could be harnessed,
enslaved to guard them
in the daylight hours
of their masters.
Or so Viktor thought
so very long ago.
...]
The nobles are upset,
my lord.
William's pestilence
has not been checked.
Werewolves have killed their slaves.
VIKTOR: Humans upset.
Tannis, please take a note
of what pain that brings me.
Yet their lost slaves
means our lost silver.
Enough. Have I not
increased our holdings tenfold
since Marcus and Amelia
took their sleep?
We will deal with the wolves
as we always have.
...]
[WEREWOLVES GROWLING]
MAN 1: Come on!
MAN 2: Come on, quickly!
[MEN YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN 3:
Fire!
MAN 4:
Close that breach.
Have you nothing better to do,
blacksmith,
than play
with weapons of war?
At least
make yourself useful.
A little gratitude, Sonja,
to the one who saved your life.
I needed no saving.
Tell me, Lucian.
Does it burden your heart
to kill your own kind?
Not at all.
They're mindless beasts,
my lord.
No brethren of mine.
VIKTOR: Really?
Father.
You are a credit
to your race. Do you
know how to remain so?
Keep your eyes
on the ground.
Get rid of that.
You were sorely missed
at council.
There are other
demands on my time,
as you know.
I see. I hope you enjoyed
your little moonlit ride.
SONJA:
I was out patrolling.
You were disobeying.
I told you to stay
within these walls.
You risk too much
for a father to ignore.
You will leave the wolves
to the Death Dealers.
And why, Father,
is my risk any greater
than theirs?
They are not my daughters,
and they are not
council members. You are.
And one day, you will become
an elder, your birthright.
Sonja, you are well
thought of at council,
but that is
a precarious thing.
They grow tired
of your games and your absences.
The dangers of the forest
are no greater than those
of the council chamber.
You will learn
the dance of politics,
to be ruthless and cunning.
And above all,
you will be loyal to your family.
To me.
After all, without
the loyalty between us,
we are no better
than the beasts at our door.
...]
MAN:
Put your back into it.
Pick that up.
Move it, you scum.
More spin.
Get up.
Lycan.
[SCREAMING]
No rest, dog.
Enough.
You dare raise your hand to me?
I said, that's enough.
So says the master's dog, hm?
You will not always
be his favorite,
and when you fall,
I will be there.
Let us hope so.
What are you looking at?
Get back to work now!
Get back to work!
MAN:
Back to work.
The matter before the council
is simple.
We are under attack.
Six times in half as many weeks,
William's kind
have reached our very walls.
What mayhem would follow
ifjust one of them got through?
Your fear, Coloman, is misplaced.
Are we not protected
by an army of immortals?
COLOMAN:
Superbly, my lord.
However, the nobles are not,
and as I have pointed out,
they are the grass
on which we graze.
If we cannot protect our humans,
it makes us look weak.
And how would you
project strength?
As our Death Dealers
patrol the night,
so our daylight guards
can patrol the day.
Lycans patrol outside the walls?
Have you lost your mind?
They are born of beasts,
and the savagery
of this despicable fact
cannot be bred away.
I think your fear of this idea
is misplaced.
We can create
a privileged class of Lycans.
Greater rations, finer quarters,
and put them under
the hand of one we trust.
Perhaps your pet, Lucian.
The one who saved
your daughter's life today.
In fact, I think we should
hear her thoughts on this matter.
Hm.
She seems
to have been needed elsewhere.
Find her.
I will take your suggestion
under advisement.
Thank you, my lord.
It would be gratifying
to be able to
reassure the nobles
when they arrive tomorrow
that we have
their interests at heart.
MAN 1: Move it!
MAN 2: Move it!
MAN 3:
Go on, slowpoke.
Over there. There.
MAN 2: Move it!
MAN 1: Don't go slow. Keep going.
[GRUNTS]
Move it along!
My lady?
...]
SONJA:
Is it true what you told my father,
that you
feel nothing when you kill them?
They're just animals,
incapable of thought or feeling,
so why should I
feel anything for them?
Sonja, if I were to leave from here,
would you come with me?
Leave?
Do not say that.
Do not even think it.
They would hunt you down
and they would
mark you like all the others.
Not if I could remove this.
Look.
I made it.
This will be my freedom.
Lucian, promise me
you won't use it.
Please.
Is that your answer, then?
You will not come.
So you want me
to stay here for you?
Like this, like an animal?
Lucian.
Vampire and Lycan,
we are both children of Corvinus,
yet my family are slaves.
I will use this key,
and I will leave this place,
but I can never
be without you now.
...]
[WEREWOLVES GROWLING]
VIKTOR: Any news of my daughter?
She's most defiant.
She refuses to see me.
Will not answer her door.
Why are the young so blind?
She risks her seat
on the council,
and for what?
I cannot imagine.
We must prepare, my lord.
Human nobles are
on their way.
It's sharp.
No wolf will stand before it.
Ready the horses.
Let someone else go.
Why?
Last night, after I left you...
Just let someone else go.
In case it had escaped
your notice, blacksmith,
I am quite capable
of looking after myself.
And besides,
you can watch over me
from the wall.
MAN:
Get your back to the rear.
Lady Sonja, your father
has ordered you to stay behind.
I intend to see our guests
safely through the gate.
Gate master.
This is not a request.
Your father is ruler of the coven.
So he keeps reminding me.
Hah!
MAN:
Get back!
Careful, blacksmith,
lest your eyes
betray your secret.
Steady. Steady.
Shut it, my child. Shut it.
Form up!
No.
Get your men out there now!
Down, boy.
Your leash is too tight.
Step away.
There's too many of them.
They'll be massacred.
Stop him!
MAN:
Ride out. Ride out.
[GROWLING]
Easy.
Dimitri.
[YELLING]
[THUDS]
[SCREAMING]
[YELLS]
SONJA:
Lucian!
LUCIAN:
Sonja!
Lucian, no.
[GROWLING]
No, stop!
He did it to save me.
Am I not master of this house?
You know you are forbidden
to remove your shackle.
Yes.
Yet you break my law
after I gave you your life.
Your days of plush living
are over, slave.
Father, leave him be.
I told you...
Hold your tongue!
You have defied me
for the last time.
Get her out of here.
Burn the bodies.
Burn them all.
...]
VIKTOR:
For removing the collar,
30 lashes.
You have stung me, Lycan,
with your betrayal.
You were like a son to me.
I gave you your life.
You gave me chains.
I would have thought, after all
these years, you would have known
you cannot have one
without the other.
Do it.
I told you
I'd be there when you fell.
[WHIP CRACKING]
[YELLS]
What?
Stop this.
He is one of our protectors.
They are but beasts themselves.
This could stir up the others.
Let them stir. Do you fear them?
Believe me, it will be worse
if we do not punish them.
Do you see now, Coloman?
You would trust them
outside the walls?
We cannot even trust them inside.
By my count, that's 21.
Continue.
...]
MAN 1:
Oh, what a terrible sound.
MAN 2:
Bloody stink.
Stay away from him,
or they'll punish you too.
Your concern for Lucian
was most touching.
A slave.
He had just saved my life.
Was it not you who told me
to show a little gratitude?
And yourself?
Have you no gratitude
for the one who saved
your daughter's life?
I am awash with it.
That he lives shows the breadth
of my magnanimity.
Were it any
other circumstances,
I would have had him fed
in pieces to his own kind.
But his punishment is now over.
He will be freed.
Freed?
Your judgment
is clouded, Sonja.
We do not keep order
with sentiment.
Lucian was forbidden
to remove his collar,
and yet he did so,
for however fine a reason.
He will remain in prison,
a cautionary tale.
Janosh and the other nobles
will soon arrive.
Your presence is expected.
I saw what
you did out there.
Very brave
for a human.
Have you come
across them before?
Only in stories.
Were you not afraid of them?
Yes,
but I wanted to live.
Are you afraid of me?
Yes.
Well, do not be.
I will not bite...
much.
You are like them?
No.
A Lycan, yes,
but not like them.
Those you fought with
tonight were animals,
the spawn of William.
Purebloods, if you will.
No trace of human left.
Savage, mindless beasts.
As it has been told.
But I saw you.
They obeyed you.
Yes.
Yes, they did.
SONJA:
Hey.
Oh, you should not be here.
I had to.
My love, I'm sorry.
Your back.
No, no, I'm all right.
This is my fault. If
I had not gone out...
Then you would not be who you are.
This is not your fault.
I cannot remain here.
I have to leave this place.
My father will be watching you
now more than ever.
What about your Death Dealers,
are there none that you can trust?
Unfortunately, their loyalty
to my father is greater
than their loyalty to me.
Tannis.
Tannis cannot be trusted.
No, Tannis, he knows about us.
How?
I have no idea.
But if he still has not
told your father, then that
must mean he wants something.
Sonja, find out what it is.
Bring them in.
Janosh.
Do you not own
the largest silver mine
in these lands?
It has been overrun, my lord.
Our workers infected,
turned to beasts.
VIKTOR:
Most unfortunate,
and costly.
I think half the rights to your mine
should cover
the expense of our assistance.
What assistance?
We have all seen
the fires on the way here.
We have learned of the deaths
of Baron Covasha and his family.
The wolves are at
your door as well.
So why should I pay tribute
when you cannot so much
as protect your own house?
You have all but
bled me dry already.
We have all heard the stories.
Look into his eyes.
They are true.
This place is cursed.
They are no more human
than the devils
that invade our lands.
If devils you call us,
rest assured,
better the devil you know.
Unhand me.
Certainly.
...]
Would anyone else
like to be heard?
Toss it here.
Bring food to these filthy mongrels.
Here you go.
Eat it up like dogs.
[GUARDS LAUGHING]
MAN:
Like dogs.
We are not animals.
Is this what you want, to be their
entertainment, their playthings?
Their pets.
Cowering beneath the whip
and then fighting
amongst ourselves.
Is this what you want?
I have lived
by their rules my entire life.
I've protected them,
envied them.
And for what?
To be treated like an animal.
We are not animals!
We do have a choice.
We can choose
to be more than this.
We can be slaves
or we can be Lycans!
VIKTOR:
Morning is upon us, my child.
It's time we left
this wretched night behind.
Gladly.
There are some
difficult decisions ahead.
I would like
your help with one of them.
Of course, Father.
With Lucian gone,
we must promote
another Lycan in his place.
Gone?
Coloman thinks
he will stir the others.
We must remove him.
That will be difficult.
He has been with us so long.
Perhaps Gyorg.
Or Thrasos.
They would be
trustworthy.
Excellent suggestions.
I will consider them strongly.
You, my child,
are the most precious
thing in my heart.
...]
What have you told my father?
What have you told him?
Nothing.
Why?
Why what?
Why have you told him nothing?
Would your father
welcome the man
who brought him news
that his beloved daughter
was consorting
with a Lycan?
He isn't well known
for his gratitude.
And I am not yet in a position
to use this for my benefit.
What sort of benefit?
There are 12 council seats.
And we don't die often.
Sadly, no.
So, what if I gave up
my seat at council?
Simply left it to you?
Why would you do that?
Can you keep a secret?
I will need something in return.
Two minutes.
Any longer is too risky.
I'm sorry.
There was no other way.
So Tannis?
You were right. He will
help us in exchange for
a seat on the council.
Your father knows nothing?
I'm sure of it.
Sonja, this can work.
Lucian, it has to.
I think some of the others
will come with me.
Sabas and Xristo, the human Raze.
My love...
I'm certain I can...
Lucian, there is no time.
My father will have you
killed tomorrow,
after the humans are turned.
You must leave at sunrise.
And you?
The important thing is you stay alive.
The best chance you have
is when Viktor and
the Death Dealers sleep.
I will be safely at
my father's side when you go.
TANNIS:
Hurry.
If this plan works,
I'll meet you in three days'
time, after the sun sets.
There's a clearing
by the river.
I'll meet you there.
And if it doesn't?
I will meet you at the clearing.
...]
MAN:
Face the wall.
Get out.
MAN: You animals.
You. Get back.
Be brave, human.
TANNIS:
You know what your problem is?
You don't understand
the natural order of things.
Things change.
Be ready when they do.
Consider it a parting gift.
[GROWLING]
Wait.
Do you not realize
this is a gift
I am giving you?
RAZE:
It's a curse.
What have they done to us?
You'll find out soon enough.
They turned us into... Like you?
Yes.
Why?
He wants to use you
for his own protection.
I will die first.
Well, that may not happen.
The time has come.
At sunrise,
I leave this place.
Anyone willing to take
the risk may follow me.
There is a new life waiting
beyond these walls, my friend,
and you can be a part of it,
one of us,
or stay and serve them.
MAN:
The guards are coming.
New dogs today.
Let's see how they look.
You've come too late.
He's already gone.
[SCREAMING]
[LUCIAN GROWLING]
Are you with me?
[CHEERING]
...]
LUCIAN:
Sabas, Xristo, free the others.
The rest of you with me.
Freedom is yours.
Move!
This way.
Down here.
All right, move. Run, run, run.
Keep moving.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Keep going. Move.
MAN:
Fire.
Raze.
There is nothing you can do.
I will come back. I promise you.
No!
My lord.
My lord, Lucian is escaping.
[YELLS]
Forest, go. Go!
My lord.
MAN 1:
Move here. Move it.
You, get in there.
MAN 2: Move.
MAN 3: Are all these accounted for?
MAN 4: Each and every one.
VIKTOR:
Tannis.
Come on. Move.
TANNIS:
Yes, my lord?
Where is the key
I gave you for this?
I locked it in the armory myself.
How, then, is it open?
I have no idea.
I think I have.
Kill him.
No.
Please.
Check the armory.
There has to be
an explanation.
Show me.
I've never been outside the walls.
LUCIAN:
Well, enjoy it
while you can, Xristo.
Because soon enough
we're gonna have to
fight our way back in.
We did not all make it out,
and I will not leave
our brothers to rot back there.
We humiliated Viktor.
It is they who will pay the cost.
But we were lucky
to make it out alive.
And there's but a handful of us.
We have no weapons.
True, for now.
The noble who brought you here,
can you lead us back to his estate?
Yes.
Good. Come on. Come on.
...]
It has to be here.
I put it here.
Here.
He must have
made another one.
I never doubted you.
Now, I have no wish
to remove one shackle
from around your necks
only to replace it
with one of my own.
You have a choice.
You can run and hide
or you can stay and fight.
Any man who fights with me
shall have his freedom
and, if he wishes it,
immortality.
MAN 1:
Pick up your weapons.
Together we're strong.
There are other estates
to the west of here.
I want you to go there.
See how many will join us.
I will meet you back here
in two days' time.
MAN 2: Put it over there.
MAN 3: Over here.
[WEREWOLVES GROWLING]
SONJA:
Father.
Did I startle you? I'm sorry.
No.
You did not.
It occurs to me
that I have been thoughtless.
So deep have I been in my own
anguish at Lucian's betrayal,
I gave no thought
to your feelings.
My feelings?
They worm their way
into our lives,
and we forget the travesty
of their birth.
I myself had tenderness
towards Lucian.
He could have
been anything.
A Death Dealer, perhaps.
Yes.
Perhaps.
But he was not as we are,
was he?
Did you help him escape?
Help him?
Of course not.
Are you lying to me?
There are many things
that I have done
against your will,
but he is a Lycan.
I'm sorry, my dear,
but you leave me no choice.
[SCREAMING]
Father, please...
I wanted to believe your lies
though I knew it could not be true.
Not my own daughter.
How could you?
Father,
I love him.
You have betrayed me!
To be with an animal!
I loved you more than anything!
She does not leave this room!
No. You're under orders to wait.
Here.
This rate, we'll have enough men
by the end of the week.
Has there been any sign of Sonja?
Nothing.
She should have
been here by now.
With respect, Lucian, I do not see
the wisdom in waiting for her.
She's not one of us.
Have you forgotten
she is the one who set us free?
But she is a vampire.
If she has deceived you,
she could lead them here.
Death Dealers
will undoubtedly be on the hunt,
and they will eventually find us,
but not by her doing.
I trust Sonja with my life,
and as long as I'm in
command, so shall you.
Told you not to say anything.
Lucian has sacked two estates
in Brashov, my lord, and made off
with the contents of their armories.
The slaves have joined his ranks.
COLOMAN:
Freedom is as much a disease
as William's pestilence.
You need to bring your pet back.
Thank you, Coloman.
The obvious escaped me.
I do not need to lift a finger.
Lucian will return
of his own free will.
I have something he wants.
My lady.
Luka. What is it? Where is she?
Sonja has been arrested.
He knows about the two of you.
He will kill her.
I thought you should know.
Nothing yet, my lord.
RAZE: It is a trap. You know that.
I will not let her die alone.
They followed you here, Lucian.
If you go, we will lose them.
Let me tell you
a secret, my friend.
They thought they followed me.
What they truly followed
was the idea of being free.
That's what brought them here.
Now, you can hold them
together until I get back,
and lead them if I do not.
...]
[GROANS]
[MAN GRUNTING]
Are you all right?
Yes.
But Lucian, you were free.
Not without you.
We have to go now.
My lord,
your daughter has escaped.
Of course she has.
This way.
That one.
Yes, sir.
[YELLS]
Now.
How dare you
raise your hand to me?
I do not want this.
I am your father.
Do you think you can defeat me?
I don't want to defeat you.
Killing me won't save
your precious Lycan.
Please call off your men,
for the sake of your grandchild.
A miracle, Father.
A union of the bloodlines.
I curse the day your mother gave
her life to bring you into this world.
That thing inside you
is a monstrosity.
LUCIAN:
Sonja!
VIKTOR:
This is over.
Remove him.
Do you understand
what you have done?
This night was not about you.
It was about him.
I could have given Lucian
to the council.
They need never have known
of your indiscretion, but after this,
never.
LUCIAN:
No!
If I had not left,
none of this would have happened.
Then you would not be who you are.
You were right.
No one should live a life like this.
Others are free because of you.
Things are forever changed
because of what you have done.
But I have failed you.
No.
Lucian, my love,
you have not failed me.
The choices I made
have led me here.
Not you.
You said yourself there are risks
that you were willing to take for me,
as was I for you.
For us.
MAN:
Open the door.
[DOOR OPENS]
No.
MAN: Get up.
No. No.
MAN: Come on. Come on.
LUCIAN:
No. I'll kill you.
All of you!
...]
The accused has
committed high treason
against the coven.
She has consorted with animals.
She has abetted in their escape.
I have saved this coven
many times over.
You have killed your own kind.
And you've commingled
bloodlines,
resulting in the thing
germinating within you.
Your past glory does not excuse
your present guilt,
nor does your station
as a council member.
The punishment for
these crimes is death.
How vote you?
Aye.
MAN: Aye.
She's your daughter.
Aye.
COLOMAN:
Take her to the chamber.
No, you... You cannot do this.
MAN:
My lady, come with us.
Come quietly, please.
Viktor.
Viktor. No!
No, Viktor!
...]
[SCREAMS]
No.
Lucian.
[RUMBLING]
No, Sonja.
Don't. Just look at me.
Keep your eyes on me, Sonja.
Look at me!
I love you.
As I love you.
Your face will not be here
when this is over, will it?
Goodbye, my love.
No.
No!
Sonja!
...]
Fetch my knives.
Yes, my lord.
[GROWLING]
My lord.
[RUMBLING]
[GROWLING]
[MEN YELLING]
...]
Go. Go. Quickly. Go.
[SCREAMING]
Now go free the others. Go!
Follow me.
Do you want your revenge?
MEN: Yeah.
It is out there. Now go.
We have greater concerns
than your precious scrolls.
Go to the elders, now!
Kill the dogs!
Viktor.
...]
You defiled my daughter.
I loved her!
You killed her!
I should have crushed you
under my heel the day
you were born.
Yes, you should have...
but you didn't.
...]
MAN:
Lucian!
Lucian.
[MEN CHEERING]
It is finished.
No.
This is just the beginning.
...]
MAN:
But let me tell you a little something
about your beloved dark father.
He's the one who killed your family.
Not the Lycans.
But when he got to you,
he just couldn't bear the thought
of draining you dry.
You, who reminded him so much
of his precious Sonja,
the daughter
he condemned to death.
WOMAN:
Lies.
...]
[GENGHIS TRON'S
"BOARD UP THE HOUSE
(RENHOLDER REMIX)" PLAYS]
[GHOSTS ON THE RADIO'S
"STEAL MY ROMANCE" PLAYS]
Underworld.Rise.Of.The.Lycans 2009.720p.BluRay.x264-CROSSBOW.English
Upload to subscene.com by ViSTA™-VNHD